Finally, inner peace.
Now what?
Kai, old friend.
Master Oogway.
Our battle ended
500 years ago!
Well, now I'm ready
for a rematch.
Took you long enough!
(LAUGHS)
(GROWLS)
(YELLING)
(GRUNTS)
You've grown stronger.
500 years in the Spirit Realm,
you pick up a thing or two.
I have taken the chi
of every master here.
(GASPS) No!
Yes.
And soon I will have
your power, too.
When will you realize?
The more you take,
the less you have.
(GRUNTS)
(KAI GRUNTING)
With your chi,
I will finally be able
to return to the mortal world.
And this time,
you won't be there
to stop me.
(SIGHS)
It was never my destiny
to stop you.
I have set another
on that path.
Then I will find him,
and take his chi, too.
- Oh, no!
- What's happening?
To your battle stations! Go! Go! Go!
Fire crossbows!
Fire!
Tai Lung is free! I must warn Shifu.
You're not going anywhere!
Neither is he!
- Let go of me!
- Bring it up!
Wait! Bring it back!
- He's coming this way!
- He won't get far. Archers!
We're dead. So very, very dead.
Not yet we're not. Now!
- Can we run now?
- Yes.
I'm glad Shifu sent you.
I was beginning to think
I'd been forgotten.
Fly back there and tell them
the real Dragon Warrior
is coming home.
- Tell me what happened that night.
- What night?
- That night.
- Ah, that night.
Yes! We're talking
about the same night, right?
Yes, I was there. Yes. I watched
as your parents abandoned you.
It's a terrible thing.
I believe it went something like this.
Here's your New Year's gift.
Hope you like it,
‘cause you can't return it.
Po? What's he doing here?
Return it! Return it!
Are you willing to die
to find the truth?
You bet I am.
Although I'd prefer not to.
We got them. Go!
You looking for me?
I said that too soon, didn't I?
Pol!
Po, get away from him.
I'll get up. Here we go.
- No more running, Shen.
- So it seems.
Now... answers.
Oh, you want to know so badly.
You think knowing will heal you, huh?
Fill some crater in your soul?
Well, here's your answer.
Your parents didn't love you.
But here...
...let me heal youl!
No!
Wings of Surveillance!
Why do you do that?
Do what?
Just because you say
"Wings of" before something,
it doesn't mean that you're
doing a special move.
It's like me saying
"Antenna of Power"
or "Thorax of
Making Sandwiches."
Wings of Disagreement.
Whoa! There.
CRANE: Master Bear,
Master Chicken, Master Croc!
What are you doing out here?
(CLUCKING) Jade creatures
attacked our villages.
(CLUCKING)
We've tracked them here.
Stop!
They must be in there.
Master Shifu strongly
advised us
(ROARING)
(YELLING)
not to engage.
We've gotta get in there.
But Master Shifu said...
You're seriously afraid?
Even Master Chicken's going
in there! And he's a chicken.
(CLUCKING)
(CLUCKS LOUDLY)
(GASPS) That's it.
I'm going in.
Mantis! We have
orders not to...
They need our help!
Come on.
I'll go high,
you go low.
(WHISPERING) No, wait.
Fear the bug!
All right, you little...
Uh-oh!
Hold on, buddy. I'm coming!
Antenna of Power!
Ah! It didn't work!
Mantis!
Mantis?
(WHISPERING) Mantis.
(GASPS)
(WHISTLING)
(GRUNTING)
(SNORTS)
Your chi is strong.
Just like your friend,
the bug.
(GASPS) Mantis.
(CRANE SCREAMING)
He wasn't just a student.
Shifu found him as a cub
and he raised him as his son.
And when the boy showed
talent in kung fu,
Shifu trained him.
He believed in him. He told him
he was destined for greatness.
It was never enough for Tai Lung.
He wanted the Dragon Scroll.
But Oogway saw darkness
in his heart and refused.
Outraged, Tai Lung
laid waste to the valley.
He tried to take the scroll by force.
And Shifu had to destroy
what he had created.
But how could he?
Shifu loved Tai Lung
like he had never loved anyone before.
Or since.
This battle is between you and me.
So, that is how it's going to be.
That is how it must be.
I rotted in jail for 20 years
because of your weakness!
Obeying your master is not weakness!
You knew I was the Dragon Warrior.
You always knew.
But when Oogway said otherwise,
what did you do?
What did you do?
Nothing!
You were not meant to be the Dragon
Warrior! That was not my fault!
Not your fault?
Who filled my head with dreams?
Who drove me to train
until my bones cracked?
Who denied me my destiny?
It was never my decision to make!
It is now.
Give me the scroll!
I would rather die.
All I ever did, I did to make you proud!
Tell me how proud you are, Shiful
Tell me!
I have...
I have always been proud of you.
From the first moment, I've been
proud of you.
And it was my pride
that blinded me.
I loved you too much
to see what you were becoming,
what I
was turning you into.
I'm...
I'm sorry.
I don't want your apology.
I want my scroll!
What?
Where is it?
Dragon Warrior has taken the scroll
halfway across China by now.
You will never see that scroll, Tai Lung.
Never.
The only way out is up.
What?
Follow me! Come on!
Where are they going?
- To the top!
- Come on! Keep going!
Here we go!
- You idiot!
- My nose!
Call in the wolves! All of them!
I want them ready to move!
The Year of the Peacock begins now!
Right now?
‘Cause it's the middle of the year,
so you'd only get like
a half of the Year of the Peacock.
And this is the Year, of course,
of the Peacock.
Happy New Year, sir.
Get the wolves ready.
We're loading the ships now.
Now!
Now, now, now, now, now!
Move! Move, move, move, move!
This way.
Let's go.
Fire!
Inner peace.
Again!
Yeah!
Kill him! Somebody kill him!
What? No. No!
Keep firing! Keep firing!
Skadoosh.
How did you...?
How did you do it?
You know, you just keep your elbows up
and keep the shoulders loose.
Not that. How did you find peace?
I took away your parents. Everything.
I scarred you for life.
See, that's the thing, Shen.
Scars heal.
No, they don't. Wounds heal.
Oh, yeah. What do scars do?
They fade, I guess?
- I don't care what scars do.
- You should, Shen.
You gotta let go of that stuff from
the past, 'cause it just doesn't matter.
The only thing that matters
is what you choose to be now.
You're right.
Then I choose... this!
That was pretty hard-core.
Oh, you wanna spare me?
How about you spare me
the chit-chat?
All right? Let's do this.
I'm going to take your chi,
then the chi
of every panda in the...
Oh! Chit-chat!
In this...
Chitty-chitty chat-chat.
In...
Chat, chat, chat.
In the...
Chit-chat!
Oh, you pudgy little...
(GROWLS)
Round them all up.
(GASPS) Oh, no. It's true.
You guys have all been
turned green!
Except for you, Mantis.
You were already green.
Now?
Wait for the signal.
(YELLS)
Here we go!
(SNORTS)
Dumpling Squad!
Ready?
Go time!
Belly!
Gong!
BOTH: Whoo!
Seriously?
Yeah! Whoo!
We did it! Whoo-hoo!
Sorry, Crane.
(CLUCKS)
(LAUGHS)
(GRUNTS)
(YELPS)
Spring Roll Squad!
Time for some takeout!
(ALL GRUNTING)
(CLUCKS)
(ALL CHEERING)
PO: Yoo-hoo!
Over here, Mr. Jombie!
(LAUGHING)
I don't know who
you are, either.
Noodle Squad!
Get ready to dance
with danger!
(YELLS)
Oh, sweet!
(EXCLAIMING IN DISBELIEF)
Stripy Baby!
(GASPS) Oh.
Whee!
(GRUNTING)
(GIGGLING)
Do it.
You're mean!
BAO: Fire!
(GROWLING)
BAO: Fire in the hole!
Oh!
Yes!
All right, kids!
You got it, guys!
Oh, no! Master Shifu!
I can't hit Shifu!
I can!
And so can I.
BOTH: Double-Dad Defense!
Left, Dad!
Right, Dad!
Thanks, Dad!
Back at you, Dad.
We've got this, son!
(LAUGHS) Go, Dads!
LI: Yeah!
Yeah! (LAUGHS)
We got them now.
(SNORTS) Stop. Stop! Enough!
Get out...
(LAUGHING)
(GASPS)
Let's finish this.
BOTH: That's our boy!
(GRUNTS)
Sorry, buddy. Gotta send you
back to the Spirit Realm.
Skadoosh!
Okay, that didn't work.
Let me try one more time.
Skadoosh! Skadoosh. Skadoosh.
Skadoo... What the...
Hold on, wait!
It's working.
No. No!
(IMITATING CHOKING)
(LAUGHING)
No, it's not.
Did Oogway teach you
that little trick?
Too bad.
It only works on mortals.
And I am a Spirit Warrior.